ORION WILLS

Data Scientist



512-992-5002







Orion is a problem solver with a talent for answering challenging questions in an actionable manner. He is an excellent team leader with the unique ability to find solutions and deliver them in a meaningful way to stakeholders. Orion has twenty years of consultative client-facing experience and now data science. Soft skills have always been a strength.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python pandas **MySQL** Numpy

Bash Sci-Kit Learn

Spark SciPy

EXPERIENCE

OAK CREEK HOMES

Marketing Specialist 03/2017 - 08/2018 Successfully managed development of innovative online marketing strategies including website development content messaging, search engine optimization, local advertising with individual dealerships, and oversight of paid vendor partnerships for successful marketing campaigns.

MATTRESS FIRM

Store Manager 03/2016 - 02/2017 Promoted to Mega Center Store Manager, in spite of being the least tenured salesperson, with responsibility for daily store operations, sales and account management with proactive engagement and nurturing of clientele to identify any opportunities for expansion of services or products.

ABLE LENDING

Director of Sales 02/2015 - 11/2015 Led daily operations for sales team of sixteen Sales Representatives with oversight of sales and promotional initiatives to increase loan originations and fundings as well as to provide optimal customer service.

YODLE, INC

Area Sales Manager 04/2010 - 07/2014 Directed area sales with oversight of sales, business development, account management, staff training and performance management focused on optimizing sales and customer service.

DATA PROJECTS

Capstone Project

Took Realtor data from over 12,000 transactions and predicted home sales volume for next 12 months

Anomaly Detection

Analyzed Codeup's curriculum logs and found anomalies in access post-graduation

Fitbit Analysis

Used time series analysis to predict health features

Customer Churn

Used clustering analysis to predict churn based on given features

Zillow Zestimate

Used clustering and regression algorithms to improve error

Powerpoint Deck Builder

Built out a presentation builder to customize presentations in PPT and VBA

Sales Dashboard

Created a dynamic sales dashboard for sales managers to monitor critical KPIs in Excel and VBA

EDUCATION

Codeup

San Antonio, TX

06/2019

Fully-immersive, project-based 18-week Data Science career accelerator that provides students with 600+ hours of expert instruction in applied data science. Students develop expertise across the full data science pipeline (planning, acquisition, preparation, exploration, modeling, delivery), and become comfortable working with real, messy data to deliver actionable insights to diverse stakeholders.